Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America PE.009
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America
1937-2006
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
PE.009
7 Linear Feet (7 boxes)
The Printed Ephemera Collection on the United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW) is an artificial collection, collected and assembled by the Tamiment Library over several decades. Known more familiarly as the UAW, this union collection consists of contracts, agreements, and constitutions as well as printed ephemera, such as fliers, brochures, leaflets, newspaper clippings, pamphlets and other publications. The materials range in date from the founding of the UAW in 1935 up to the present, spanning the various changes in affiliation the UAW had with both the American Federation of Labor (AFL) and the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO). In addition to the international and national body of the UAW, the collection contains printed material from UAW locals, notably the Detroit and Flint Michigan automobile plants, as well as materials from rank and file activity from around the United States.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Custodial History
The provenance of the materials is varied. Items were obtained through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, arrangements with labor unions and other organizations, exchanges with other libraries, and through ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff.
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW) is made up of agreements, contracts, and constitutions, as well as printed ephemera such as fliers, brochures, newspaper clippings, pamphlets and other publications.
Series I: United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, 1957-2006, consists of constitutions, by-laws, agreements, convention proceedings and decisions made by the Public Review Board as well as printed ephemera. Additionally, this series broken down by department, with material coming largely from the Education Department, the Fair Practices and Anti-Discrimination Department, and the Public Relations Department. Included from the Public Relations and Publications Department are numerous biographical sketches about leaders in the UAW. Also in this series are the fliers and other printed material put out by a number of different rank and file groups, including the Black Panther Caucus, the United National Caucus, and the Locals Opposed to Concessions group.
Series II: United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, 1939-1972 consists of material from the union at the national level including constitutions and conventions proceedings. Additionally, the material in this series is broken down by department, and like Series I, the printed material originates largely with the Education and Public Relations Departments.
Series III: United Automobile Workers of America, 1937-1951, consists of material from the founding years of the UAW. This is a smaller series consisting mainly of constitutions and liers as well as several pamphlets.
Series IV: Regions and Locals, 1937-2005, consists of material that was generated at the Regional or Local level. There is material from several locals in and around Detroit and Flint Michigan, as well as from the rank and file groups out of Local 906 from New Jersey, the Militant Solidarity Caucus and the United Black Workers.
Historical/Biographical Note
The United Automobile Workers of America (UAW) was founded in 1935, and over the next few years changed its affiliation from the American Federation of Labor to that of the Congress of Industrial Organizations. In 1937, the UAW gained recognition from the General Motors Corporation with its use of the dramatic sit-down strike, employed as both a bargaining tool and an organizing method. Membership skyrocketed following these heroic organizing campaigns and recognition was gained from the major auto manufacturing companies. In 1941, the UAW changed its name to the International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, and later in 1962, it changed the "Aircraft" to "Aerospace", though today the union is still familiarly known as the UAW. Walter Reuther served as president from 1946 until 1970 when he and his wife died tragically in an airplane crash. As of 2009, the UAW had roughly 513,000 active members and more than 575,000 retired members in the United States, Canada and Puerto Rico. There were more than 800 local unions within the UAW with over 3,100 contracts.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into four series: Series I: United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, 1957-2006; Series II: United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, 1939-1972; Series III: United Automobile Workers of America, 1937-1951; Series IV: Locals and Regions, 1937-2005. Folders are arranged alphabetically within series.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library. There is no accession record associated with this collection.
Brochures.; Circular letters.; Articles.; Decisions.; Printed ephemera.; Constitutions.; Contracts; Pamphlets.; Fliers (printed matter); Biographies.; Publications (documents); Reports.; Annual reports.; Agreements.; Labor unions; Clippings (information artifacts); International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America; International Union, United Automobile Workers of America (CIO)
- Series I: United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, 1957-2006
  - Academics Come Together (ACT) (New School University Union for Adjunct Professors), 2003-2005 (Box 1)
  - Agreements and Contracts, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Agreements and Contracts, 1969-1974 (Box 1)
  - Agreements and Contracts, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Agricultural Implement Department, 1970-1982, undated (Box 1)
  - Arbitration Services Department, 1968, undated (Box 1)
  - Autoworkers for a Better Contract, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Black Panther Caucus (Freemont, CA), undated (Box 1)
  - Circular Letters, 1965-1996 (Box 1)
  - Citizen Education Publications, 1962-1969 (Box 1)
  - Coalition for a Good Contract, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Community Action Program, 1978, undated (Box 1)
  - Community Action Program, 1987, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Community Services Department, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Collective Bargaining Convention, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Conservation and Resource Development Department, 1964-1980 (Box 1)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1966-1972 (Box 1)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1977-1983 (Box 1)
  - Constitutional Convention, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Constitutions, 1966-1977 (Box 2)
  - Constitutions, 1980-1989 (Box 2)
  - Constitutions, 1989-2006 (Box 2)
  - Education Department, 1964-1985, undated (Box 2)
  - Education Department: Outlines for Discussion Topics and Readings, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Education Department Publications (un-numbered), undated (Box 2)
  - Education Department Publications (un-numbered), 1972-1990 (Box 2)
  - Education Department Publications (#4-356), 1972-1989 (Box 2)
  - Education Department Publications (#357-397), 1965-1990 (Box 2)
  - Education Department Publications (#399-514), 1965-1990 (Box 2)
  - Fair Practices and Anti-Discrimination Department, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Fliers and Ephemera, 1965-1990 (Box 2)
  - Flint Sit-Down Strike (Anniversaries and Commemorations), 1962, 1980-1989 (Box 2)
  - Ford Employee Development and Training Program, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Health and Safety Department, 1970-1995 (Box 2)
  - International Affairs Department, 1966-1978 (Box 2)
  - International Skilled Trades Conference, 1976-1979 (Box 2)
  - Labor for Peace, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Legal Department, 1978-1980 (Box 2)
  - Legislative Department, 1965-1987 (Box 2)
  - Local Union Press Association, 1975-1993 (Box 2)
  - "Locals Opposed to Concessions", circa 1980s, undated (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles on, 1968-2005, undated (Box 2)
  - Organizing Department, undated (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets and Publications (General UAW), 1964-1990, undated (Box 2)
  - "Policies and Priorities for Progress" Series, 1967-1970 (Box 2)
  - Press Conferences, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Public Relations and Publications Department, 1964-1992 (Box 3)
  - Public Relations and Publications Department: Biographical Sketches, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Public Review Board: Annual Reports, 1961-1986 (Box 3)
  - Public Review Board: Decisions, 1958-1962 (Box 3)
  - Public Review Board: Decisions, 1963-1966 (Box 3)
  - Public Review Board: Decisions, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
  - Public Review Board: Decisions, 1970-1972 (Box 3)
  - Public Review Board: Decisions, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Public Review Board: Decisions, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - Public Review Board: Decisions, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - Public Review Board: Decisions, 1978-1980 (Box 3)
  - Public Review Board: Digest and Index (I), 1957-1968 (Box 3)
  - Public Review Board: Digest and Index (II), 1957-1968 (Box 3)
  - Publications Relating to, 1963-1990 (Box 4)
  - Purchase and Supply Department, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Rank and File, 1973-1978, undated (Box 4)
  - Rank and File, 1978-1991 (Box 4)
  - Reports of Officers, 1963-1982 (Box 4)
  - Research Library, 1973-1986 (Box 4)
  - Social Security Department, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Strike Insurance Department, 1974-1978 (Box 4)
  - United National Caucus, 1968-1979 (Box 4)
  - The Voice of New Directions, 1997
  - Veterans Committee, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Walter and May Reuther UAW Family Education Center, 1972-1990 (Box 4)
  - Women's Department, 1968-1990 (Box 4)
- Series II: United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, 1939-1972
  - Agreements and Contracts, 1941-1955 (Box 4)
  - Agreements and Contracts, 1957-1961 (Box 4)
  - Benefit Plans, 1947-1950 (Box 4)
  - Circular Letters, 1943-1957 (Box 4)
  - Collective Bargaining Convention, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1939-1947 (Box 4)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1955-1959 (Box 4)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Constitutional Convention: Social Justice Award (program with Eleanor Roosevelt signature?), 1962 (Box 4)
  - Constitutions, 1943-1949 (Box 4)
  - Constitutions, 1951-1959 (Box 4)
  - Consumer Division, undated (Box 4)
  - Directories, 1945 (Box 4)
  - Economic and Collective Bargaining Conference, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Education Department, 1946-1948, undated (Box 5)
  - Education Department, 1955-1961 (Box 5)
  - Education Department Publications (#1-10), 1943-1949, undated (Box 5)
  - Education Department Publications (#11-29), 1943-1948 (Box 5)
  - Education Department Publications (#30-69), 1943-1946, undated (Box 5)
  - Education Department Publications (#70-99), 1945-1947, undated (Box 5)
  - Education Department Publications (#100-149), 1947-1958 (Box 5)
  - Education Department Publications (#150-199), 1947-1948, undated (Box 5)
  - Education Department Publications (#200-299), undated (Box 5)
  - Education Department Publications (#300-324), 1953-1972 (Box 5)
  - Education Department Publications (#325-349), 1954-1958, undated (Box 5)
  - Education Department Publications (#350-399), 1961-1972, undated (Box 5)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt Peace Award, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Fair Practices and Anti-Discrimination Department, 1940s, undated (Box 5)
  - Fair Practices and Anti-Discrimination Department, 1950s (Box 5)
  - Fair Practices and Anti-Discrimination Department, 1960-1961 (Box 5)
  - Fliers, 1958, undated (Box 5)
  - Ford Department, 1961, undated (Box 5)
  - Full Employment Conference, 1953 (Box 5)
  - General Motors: Publications by, 1945-1961 (Box 5)
  - General Motors Department, 1943-1960 (Box 5)
  - "Get America Back to Work" Conference, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Health and Accident Department, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Housing Department, 1941-1944, undated (Box 6)
  - International Education Conference, 1952-1954 (Box 6)
  - International Education Department, 1940-1941, undated (Box 6)
  - International Education Department, 1942-1943 (Box 6)
  - International Research Department, 1944-1945 (Box 6)
  - "Labor Great Books Program", 1949-1954 (Box 6)
  - Legal Department, 1941 (Box 6)
  - National Reuther for President Committee, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles on, 1946-1958, undated (Box 6)
  - Pamphlets and Publications (General UAW), 1944-1961, undated (Box 6)
  - Political Action and Legislative Department, 1944-1945 (Box 6)
  - Press Releases, 1943-1957 (Box 6)
  - Public Relations Department, 1947-1950, undated (Box 6)
  - Public Relations Department, 1951-1952 (Box 6)
  - Public Relations Department: Press Releases, 1947-1962 (Box 6)
  - Public Review Board, 1958 (Box 6)
  - Publications Department, 1947-1958 (Box 6)
  - Publications Relating to, 1945-1956, undated (Box 6)
  - Reports of Officers, 1939-1956 (Box 6)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1948-1962, undated (Box 6)
  - Retired Workers Centers, 1956-1959, undated (Box 6)
  - Social Security Department, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Supply Department, undated (Box 6)
  - UAW-GM Special Leadership Conference, 1958 (Box 6)
  - War Policy Division, 1944, undated (Box 6)
  - Women's Auxiliaries, 1946 (Box 6)
- Series III: United Automobile Workers of America, 1937-1951
  - United Automobile Workers of America, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - United Automobile Workers of America (AFL), 1948-1950, undated (Box 7)
  - United Automobile Workers of America (AFL): Constitutions, 1947, 1951 (Box 7)
- Series IV: Regions and Locals, 1937-2005
  - Local 2 (Detroit, MI), 1942 (Box 7)
  - Local 3 (Dodge Local), 1941 (Box 7)
  - Local 7, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Local 9 (South Bend, IN), undated (Box 7)
  - Local 33, undated (Box 7)
  - Local 50 (Ypsilanti, MI), 1945, undated (Box 7)
  - Local 51 (Detroit, MI), 1941, 1946, undated (Box 7)
  - Local 155 (Detroit, MI), undated (Box 7)
  - Local 156 (Flint, MI), 1937, undated (Box 7)
  - Local 160, 1975 (Box 7)
  - Local 174 (Detroit, MI), 1982 (Box 7)
  - Local 200 (Windsor, Ontario), 1974 (Box 7)
  - Local 248, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Local 259 (Flint, MI), 1972-1995, undated (Box 7)
  - Local 297, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Local 300, 1953-1962 (Box 7)
  - Local 365 (Newark, NJ), 1943 (Box 7)
  - Local 365, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Local 430 (Westfield, MA), 1981 (Box 7)
  - Local 501, undated (Box 7)
  - Local 541 (Englewood, NJ), 1976 (Box 7)
  - Local 595 (Linden, NJ), 1951-1982 (Box 7)
  - Local 599 (Buick Local, Flint, MI), 1982 (Box 7)
  - Local 600 (Ford Local), 1951 (Box 7)
  - Local 659 (Flint, MI), 1947, 1984-1986 (Box 7)
  - Local 674 (Norwood, OH)), 1972 (Box 7)
  - Local 677 (Allentown, PA), 1957 (Box 7)
  - Local 683 (Los Angeles, CA), 1941, undated (Box 7)
  - Local 838 (Waterloo, IA), 1955, undated (Box 7)
  - Local 887 (Inglewood, CA), undated (Box 7)
  - Local 906 (NJ), 1977 (Box 7)
  - Local 906 (NJ): Militant Solidarity Caucus, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
  - Local 906 (NJ): United Black Workers, 1975, undated (Box 7)
  - Local 980, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Local 988 (Memphis, TN), 1960 (Box 7)
  - Local 1189, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Local 1295 (Riverside, NJ), 1958 (Box 7)
  - Local 1663, undated (Box 7)
  - Local 2110 (Technical, Office and Professional Union, New York, NY), 1995-1997 (Box 7)
  - Local 2110: Graduate Student Organizing Committee I, 1997- (Box 7)
  - Local 2110: Graduate Student Organizing Committee II, 1997- (Box 7)
  - Local 2200 (Detroit, MI), undated (Box 7)
  - Local 2300 (Ramada Inn, Ithaca, NY), 1990 (Box 7)
  - Local 2320 (New York, NY), undated (Box 7)
  - Local 7902 (New York, NY), 2005, undated (Box 7)
  - Region 1, circa 1984 (Box 7)
  - Region 2, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Region 3, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Region 4, 1976, undated (Box 7)
  - Region 5, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Region 8, undated (Box 7)
  - Region 9, 9a, 1945-1978, undated (Box 7)